What we just did here was to go ahead and create a computer engine in VM.
O acabamos de fazer aqui foi criar uma VM do Compute Engine
Just for the purposes of branding a few scripts.
só para registrar alguns scripts.
This is hugely wasteful.
Isso é um grande desperdício.
You don't actually have to do that.
Não precisamos fazer isso.
And let me show you something really cool.
Deixe-me mostrar algo muito legal.
If you go to the GCP console,
Se você for ao console do GCP,
you'll see this little icon here that says,
verá esse ícone pequeno que diz:
"Activate Google Cloud Shell."
"Ativar o Google Cloud Shell".
So, go ahead and click on that.
Clique nele.
And what you'll get is something called Cloud Shell.
Você terá algo chamado Cloud Shell.
And Cloud Shell is a micro VM.
E o Cloud Shell é uma micro-VM.
It's a really small tiny VM.
É uma VM muito pequena.
But it is usually enough for our purposes if all
Mas normalmente é suficiente para os nossos propósitos
we want to do is to go ahead and try out a few things,
se tudo o que quisermos fazer for experimentar algumas coisas,
run a few scripts,
executar alguns scripts,
copy a few files over from one location to another.
copiar alguns arquivos de um local para outro.
So, here we are in Cloud Shell,
Aqui estamos no Cloud Shell,
and I can essentially go ahead and do
e podemos seguir em frente e fazer
pretty much the same kinds of things that it did on the computer engine VM.
as mesmas coisas que fizemos na VM do Compute Engine.
Except, that Cloud Shell is meant for developers.
Exceto pelo fato de o Cloud Shell ser para desenvolvedores.
So, many of the things that we actually had to go install on the computer engine VM,
Por isso, muitas das coisas que tínhamos que instalar na VM do Compute Engine,
we don't need to do that here.
não instalaremos aqui.
So, for example, Git. Already there.
O Git, por exemplo. Já está aqui.
So, if you want to go ahead and get Git,
Se você quiser ter o Git,
I would just say Git clone.
é só digitar "Git clone".
We now have all of the code that we needed to have,
Agora temos todo o código que precisávamos ter,
and we can go ahead and do much of our lab that we did in computer engine.
e podemos fazer muito do que fizemos em nosso laboratório no Compute Engine.
We could just go ahead and do it in Cloud Shell.
É só fazer isso no Cloud Shell.
Now, the thing about Cloud Shell is that it's a very ephemeral VM.
O Cloud Shell é uma VM muito temporária.
If you're not using it,
Se não usá-la,
usually in under an hour, it gets recycled.
normalmente em até uma hora, ela será reciclada.
But then you can always go ahead and start another Cloud Shell.
Mas você sempre pode iniciar outro Cloud Shell.
You can get another tab in the Cloud Shell.
Você pode abrir outra guia no Cloud Shell.
This is still the same VM,
Ainda é a mesma VM,
but you now have two tabs in it.
mas agora você tem duas guias nela.
And you can run other commands in this tab.
E você pode executar outros comandos nesta guia.
So, we will be using Cloud Shell as a way to do things like starting data lab.
Usaremos o Cloud Shell como uma forma de fazer coisas como iniciar o Datalab.
It's something that you're going to do in the next lab.
É algo que faremos no próximo laboratório.